大家好
Hello there.
我是莱恩雷诺斯
I'm Ryan Reynolds.
没错
Yeah, hmm.
就是那个莱恩雷诺斯
That Ryan Reynolds.
我是一个电影演员
I'm a film actor,
我偶尔也涉足电视
occasionally I dabble in television
以及其它行业
and other industries.
我同样是一位父亲
I'm also a father.
不过我已准备好放下这一切了
But I'm ready to move on from all of that crap.
那么接下来涉足什么？
So what's next?
野生动物世界.. 就是这个
Wildlife, that's what.
不  绝不是那种夜郎自大的家伙
Nope, not these blowhards.
它们无须我的帮助
They don't need my help.
这次我是冲着这群家伙来的
I'm here for these guys.
它们皆是自然界中的替补队员
Nature's benchwarmers.
我所说的顶级怪兽
I'm talking grade-A freaks
它们的生活方式怪诞不经 超乎你的想象
and their freakin' bizarre, weird, freakshow lives.
下面让我们迎接那些隐秘的动物英雄们吧
Get ready for the Underdogs.
∮ 我想成为你隐秘的动物英雄 ∮
∮ I wanna be your underdog ∮
这些家伙简直是地球上最恶心 最怪异的动物了
These guys are the grossest, weirdest...
∮ 我不是食物链的顶级兽 可我独一无二 ∮
∮ I'm not number one, but I'm second to none ∮
它们是生命这部伟大电影中最不寻常的明星
...the most unlikely stars in the great movie of life.
∮ 英雄被过誉了  当个亡命之徒才更带劲 ∮
∮ Heroes are overrated when you are the outlaw ∮
现在是该它们大显身手的时刻
Now it's their time to shine.
∮ 因为我想成为你隐秘的动物英雄 ∮
∮ Cuz I wanna be your underdog ∮
生活中只要哪里有明目张胆的恶作剧
Wherever there isblatant mischief,
哪里有可怜的怯懦行为
wherever there is abject cowardice,
哪里有.. 难以描述的那个..
wherever there is unbearable sexual tension...
那里就有隐秘的动物英雄
that's where you'll find the underdogs.
∮ 让他们听见你的声音--青葱岁月 ∮
∮ You tell 'em, Green Day. ∮
∮ 我不是失败者  我不是失败者 ∮
∮ I'm not a loser ∮
∮ 我想成为你隐秘的动物英雄 ∮
∮ I wanna be your underdog ∮
我是莱恩雷诺斯
I'm Ryan Reynolds.
∮ 我想成为你隐秘的动物英雄 ∮
∮ I wanna be your underdog ∮
这里我要为这些怪咖们点赞
And I endorse these weirdoes.
《隐 秘 的 动 物 英 雄》
哇！见证奇迹时刻！
Wow.The miracle of birth.
这配音设计有点过分了
The sound design is a bit much. Oof.
无法想象这配音加上文字的话
Can't imagine what the closed-captioning
会是什么样的效果
would be on this.
对于幼崽来说 这是它...
For the youngster, this is the start
..充满无限可能的羚生起点
of a life of limitless possibility.
而对于父母来说 这种亲子关系的建立
And for the parent, the formation of a bond
其力量比任何外力都要强大
more powerful than any force on--
等等 啥情况？她要去哪里？
Wait, wha--? Where's she going?
不..不..不..不对!
N-n-n-no!
这位羚妈怎么跑了？
Where is she going?
别担心~她会回来的
Don't worry. She's coming back.
我敢肯定
I'm pretty sure.
要是她不回来的话 那.. 那就当我没说过
I have no i--she's probably not coming back.
但我还是对她抱有希望
But I'm hopeful.
现在看来.. 还是算了
I'm not hopeful.
在你们评论之前...做父母的真的太不容易了
But before you judge, being a parent is super hard.
突然间 需要对一个弱小无助的生命体负责
Suddenly you're responsible for a tiny, helpless life-form,
坦白说  确实令人很很害怕
and it's frankly terrifying.
如果你们正在寻找一些正确的育儿指南
If you're searching for a guide on how to do it right,
那就对了 本系列大自然中的
隐秘的动物英雄将会给你们答案
look no further than Mother Nature's underdogs.
因为不管你们有多糟糕
Because no matter how terrible you are,
你们也不可能比他们更糟
you can't be as bad as them.
父母面临的第一个难题是找到一所合适的“育婴室”
The first challenge for parents is finding a suitable nursery,
而这些白颊黑雁为了寻找一间完美的“育婴室”
and these barnacle geese are willing to travel a long way
不惜千里迢迢 翻山越岭
to find the perfect spot.
作为菜鸟父母
As a new parent,
大伙儿总会告诉你要听从自己的直觉
people always tell you to follow your instincts.
于是直觉把它们带到了格陵兰岛
And instinct has led these guys here, to Greenland.
当然 这里是一块充满岩石与冰雪
险象环生的贫瘠土地
Sure, it's a barren land of rocks, ice and darkness.
但是白颊黑雁来到这里繁衍后代
But geese have been coming here to raise kids
已有几千年的历史
for thousands of years.
根据他们的父母以往经验来看这里是首选的育雏宝地
It worked for their parents,
所以拉里和琼也打算试一试
so Larry and Joan are gonna give it a go.
拉里找到了一个绝佳的筑巢地点
Larry has found them an awesome nest site.
这里刚好远离捕食者
Just out of reach of predators.
而且这景色？
And the view?
嗯 那简直美得要死！
Well, that's to die for.
就是有一个小小的问题
There's really just one tiny thing.
可以说是微不足道的
Minuscule, really.
拉里的巢穴
Larry's nest,
离地面大约有244米高
where his tiny, flightless chicks will be born...
而他的雏鸟将在那里出生
...is approximately 800 feet off the ground.
对了  还有一个
Oh, and there's one other thing.
这几乎可以忽略不计
It's hardly worth mentioning.
偶尔会有雪崩与洪水
There is a risk of the occasional
并发的风险
avalanche/flood combo.
你可以称它作："风味雪崩"吧
It's a flavalanche, if you will.
在这种情况下  一些父母可能会
At this point, some parents might question
质疑他们对安家的的选择
their choice of home.
但他们不会！
But not these guys!
他们在峻峭的悬崖边上
They've laid their four precious eggs
产下了4枚珍贵的蛋
right on top of this razor-sharp precipice.
拉里！
Larry!
就是典型的菜鸟爸爸
Classic first-time parent.
∮ 你必须强调积极的一面 ∮
∮ You've got to accentuate the positive ∮
但直觉告诉他应该找最高的地方来筑巢
But instinct told him to find the highest spot for his nest.
直觉永远不会错的
And instinct can never be wrong.
对吗？
Right?
∮ 不要招惹"中间人"先生 ∮
∮ Don't mess with Mr. In-Between ∮
所以 当“育婴室”已经准备妥当
然后宝宝很快就要来了
So, your nursery is prepared, and the baby will soon be here.
现在是时候开始寻找合适的“托儿所”了
It's a great time to start your search for suitable childcare.
你得小心选择谁来帮你照看孩子啊
You just gotta be careful who you choose to babysit.
欢迎来到马来西亚槟城
Welcome to Penang, Malaysia.
这些无赖是一群黑叶猴
These reprobates are a troop of dusky langurs.
他们离开了丛林  迁到了城市
They left the jungles behind and moved into the city.
但你知道他们是怎么说的
But you know what they say,
你可以把动物带出野外
you can take an animal out of the wild,
但你不能剥夺动物的野性
but you can't take the wild out of the animal.
但并非每只叶猴都行为不端
But not everybody's misbehaving.
这位菜鸟妈妈放下了享乐的日子
This first-time mother has put aside her days of hedonism
全心照料她的新生儿
to focus on her newborn.
哦.. 对了  在你们问之前
Oh, oh, and before you ask,
她并没有对红毛猩猩表现出过分友好的举动
she did not get overly friendly with an orangutan;
所有的黑叶猴宝宝在出生后的最初几个月里都是橘色的
all baby langurs are orange for the first few months.
现在是时候把她的宝贝婴儿
Now the time has come to introduce her precious infant
介绍给家里的其他成员了
to the rest of the family.
比起他们的胡作非为
There's one thing that these guys like
他们更喜爱一样东西
more than all-out anarchy.
那就是婴儿
It's babies.
∮ 为之疯狂 ∮
∮ Crazy ∮
∮ 我对弹琴这事简直着迷 总是弹个没完没了 ∮
∮ I'm crazy for feeling so lonely ∮
你知道那种感觉吗？当你所有的亲戚
You know the feeling when all your relatives
都想过来用他们没洗过的
wanna come around and hold the baby
满是细菌的手去抱孩子的时候？
with their unwashed, germy hands?
好吧 如果你觉得这种情况绝对无法接受
Well, if you think you got it bad,
那你应该谢天谢地  自己不是一只黑叶猴
just be grateful you're not a langur.
∮ 疯狂地作死 ∮
∮ Crazy for tryin' ∮
因为我所说的他们喜爱婴儿
'Cause when I say they love babies,
其实是想说他们喜爱婴儿的程度
I mean they really love babies.
到达疯狂的地步
Like obsessed.
∮ ...因为钟爱你 ∮
∮ ...for loving you ∮
总之.. 哪哪都是婴儿
Just baby, baby, baby. All the time, baby.
一个个成了抢夺婴儿的狂徒
Baby-grabbing maniacs.
从他们闻到新生儿的气味那刻起
When they get a whiff of that new baby smell,
妈妈就已经失去拥抱自己宝宝的机会
mom's got zero chance of keeping a hold of him.
嗯..他们因此感到头痛 但奈之如何？
Uh, they know to support the head, right?
当一群不负责任的亲戚开始
While most parents step in
粗暴对待他们的新生儿时
when an irresponsible horde of relatives
大部分的父母都会竭力制止...
starts manhandling their newborn,
..这位黑叶猴妈妈恍然大悟
this mom is having something of an epiphany.
这是作为新手父母的必修课
Learning a lesson every new parent must:
忙中偷闲不失为一个好主意
it's okay to take a little time for yourself.
我说的是自己  不是你哦
I'm talking to me right now, not you.
即便这就好比是...
Even when that means passing
..要把你最珍贵的宝贝交给奶奶手里也在所不惜
your precious little nugget off to grandma.
嘿 奶奶！
Hey, grammy!
她会不会有点过分了
She may be a little much,
总是觉得自己做的永远都是对的
and thinks she knows best all the time.
而事实上.. 所谓的免费的托儿服务
就真的是免费的托儿服务！！
But free childcare is, in fact, free childcare,
所以 只要能给妈妈一点私人时间就行 对吧？
so, whatever gets mom a little me time, right?
怎么可能会出错呢？
What could possibly go wrong?
好吧.. 奶奶把宝贝交给了.. 我想那是迈克叔叔
Well, grandma passes him to...I think that's Uncle Mike.
谁知道他正在假释期间外出活动
Didn't know he was out on parole.
然后迈克叔叔转手交给另一个家伙
And Uncle Mike passes him to whoever that is.
似乎他一点也不靠谱
Doesn't seem totally trustworthy.
可能在监视名单上
Probably on a watchlist.
但孩子妈妈看到的只是
一个获得悠闲时光的机会
But all mom sees is the chance for some sweet, sweet freedom.
但接下来.. 这家伙所做的事
惊呆了小伙伴们.. 他居然“越线”了
But then, whoever that is crosses a line.
我所说的“越线”
When I say crosses a line,
指的是他抱着孩子
I mean literally carries the baby
跨越一条高压线
across a high-voltage power line.
我的意思是
I mean, what the
遵循自然界中优胜劣汰的原则
这些作死的家伙怎么活到今天的？
is natural selection doing all day?
对吧？
Right?
于是孩子妈妈决定今天家族成员之间的社交活动就此结束
And mom decides that's enough family bonding for today.
然后她把孩子接了回来
And goes to get her baby back.
对于黑叶猴来说
养育幼崽需要整个群体的共同努力
For langurs, it takes a village to raise kids.
但每个父母都有自己的底线
But every parent has their limit.
不要越线.. 麦克叔叔..
Boundaries, Uncle Mike.
不要越线
Boundaries.
所以.. 你的育婴室
So, you've got the nursery
和托儿所都安排妥当了.. 太棒了！
and the childcare sorted, that's great!
但是育儿的成本很高
But kids are expensive.
除非你有一个又老又有钱
So unless you've got a very old, very rich relative
要去卖喊鸭蛋的亲戚
about to kick the bucket,
否则你得想办法买单
you're gonna need a plan on how to pay for it all.
为了有效地管理家庭
In order to manage a home efficiently,
许多家庭主妇会关注家庭的财务情况
many a housewife keeps track of the family's money
并计划家庭开支 储蓄
and plan its spending and saving.
你是说预算吗？
You mean a budget?
听起来很不错
Sounds impressive.
那你知道动物界中那个家伙
You know who is excellent
在管理家庭财务方面最出色吗？
at balancing the books?
那就是.. 收割鼠
Harvest mice.
对 这也不是我第一次猜测 至少是50次以上
Yeah, not my first guess either. Not my 50th.
这位名叫"蒂克勒鼠"女士已经产下了八只幼崽
Mrs. Ticklemouse here has got eight babies,
正躲在她舒适的草窝里
hidden away in her cozy nest of grass.
她知道需要收集多少物资
And she knows exactly how much she needs to gather
才能满足他们的温饱
to make sure they're warm and well fed.
哦 老天！
Oh, jeez!
《国家地理》频道即时播报：这是一只狡黠的小家伙...
Oh, National Geographic, you little vixen,
..大家千万一定别被表象矇骗...
that scared the...
嗯.. 别担心.. 她很好
Well, don't worry, she's fine.
她马上就要起来了...
She's gonna get up any second now.
你瞧.. 那里.. 她在动
You see, there, she's moving.
哦.. 我明白了.. 这是个误导!
Oh, I get it, it was a misdirect.
愿它灵魂安息  阿门！
R.I.P.
来认识一下真正的会计专家——
Meet the real experts at accounting,
埋葬虫先生与夫人吧
Mr. and Mrs. Burying Beetle,
还有他们的同伴搭乘顺风车的螨虫
plus their entourage of hitchhiking mites,
这些本不该属于本系列的内容
who aren't in this section
但实在太恶心了 不得不提及一下
but are too gross not to acknowledge.
∮ 在月黑风高的夜晚里 ∮
∮ In the cool of the evening ∮
∮ 仿佛一切都变得更加美妙 ∮
∮ When everything is gettin' kind of groovy ∮
此时此刻.. 我不得不说
Right now, I'm afraid to say
他们正在蒂克勒鼠女士身上跳着光腚舞蹈
that they're doing the no-pants dance on Mrs. Ticklemouse.
等等
Wait.
《国家地理》你们居然专门开通一个平台来
National Geographic, you guys devoted a whole channel
谈论大自然 真是太令人恶心了
to Mother Nature, and it's just absolutely disgusting.
嗯..
Mmm.
就像大自然中最令人厌恶的殡葬承办人
And like nature's nastiest undertakers,
它们在尸体上做完甜蜜的爱
having made sweet, sweet love on the corpse,
然后埋葬它
they then bury it.
因为...太恶心了
Because... gross.
他们为什么这样做呢？
And why do they do this?
因为"蒂克勒鼠"女士的尸体能够提供它们
Because the body of Mrs. T will provide all the resources
繁衍后代所需要的一切资源
their growing family needs to support itself,
如果预算合理的话
if they budget properly.
埋葬虫夫人产卵的数量正好是
Mrs. Beetle lays the exact number of eggs
他们预算的尸体所能承受的范围
that they think the corpse can sustain.
几天后 它们的孵化出
And three days later, they hatch,
这群可爱的小宝宝
into these adorable bundles of joy.
妈妈和爸爸负责喂养它们
Mom and dad get to work feeding them,
呃...嗯...把...呃...
by--mmh--regurgitating Miss--huh--
"蒂克勒鼠"女士的腐肉
Mrs. Ticklemouse
反刍到...反刍到他们的嘴里
directly into... into their mouths.
我能行..  我能行.. 我是个男子汉
I can do this, I can do this, I can do this, I'm a big boy.
我只是还没有做好心理准备
A little heads up would have been nice.
我看得出这是很好的育儿方式
I don't really see any terrible parenting here.
我看到这些幼虫专心地进食 食物充足
I see attentive parents, plenty of food,
还有与它们父母间的亲密接触
lots of skin-to-skin contact,
你们知道 这是最基本的常识
you know, this is textbook stuff.
我意思是 你不能在玻璃房子里扔石头
I mean, you don't throw rocks from glass houses.
但有一个问题
But there's a problem.
这些小家伙的胃口正在与日俱增
These little tikes have gotten greedy.
毕竟"蒂克勒鼠"女士那具臭气熏天的尸体
There's only so much of Mrs. Ticklemouse's fetid corpse
反刍到孩子们每张贪得无厌的嘴里的食物有限
being masticated and then regurgitated
恐怕难以支撑它们的成长
into your child's welcoming mouth to go around.
幸运的是 爸爸妈妈已经找到了解决生活费用
Luckily mom and dad have a way to get the budget
超支的办法
back on track.
而遗憾是的
And I'm afraid to say,
方法就是.. 吃掉自己的孩子
well, it's eating their own children.
从那个最贪婪的家伙开始
Starting with the greedy ones.
奇怪的是 这倒没引起我的困惑
Which weirdly doesn't bother me that much,
嗯那 ..我也不知道为什么
I don't know why that one... mm-mm.
如果这看起来很残忍
If it seems extreme,
那是因为它.. 嗯..它是.. 应该是..
它真的是.. 确实是超级残忍
that's because it, well, it's, it is, it's, it's extreme.
但是少了一张嘴吃饭
But with one less mouth to feed,
其它孩子生活得更好吃得更多长得
更胖更壮更抗揍.. 生存机率大大的
the other kids have a better chance at survival.
而且它们的父母甚至可能有能力供它们上大学
And their parents might even be able to afford college.
这称不称得上为良好的育儿方式？
Does it count as good parenting?
你们自己来决定
I'll let you decide.
回到这里 拉里对于即将成为父亲
So how's Larry facing up to the prospect
会有怎样的表现呢？
of first-time fatherhood?
瞧他熊样 吓得直拉裤子了
He's literally crapping himself.
这种情况在很多初为人父者身上都曾发生过
It's happened to many a new father.
幸运的是 琼是个天才
Fortunately, Joan is a natural.
目前 她已经孵了这窝蛋
She's been sitting on their clutch of four eggs
整整10天
for 10 days now,
每隔1小时都会小心翼翼翻动它们
lovingly turning them every hour,
让它们保持温暖和透气
keeping them warm and safe,
尽管拉里在“房子”方面的决策存在疑问
despite Larry's questionable real estate decision.
但是琼饿了
But Joan is hungry.
所以 当她外出觅食时...
So, while she pops out to feed...
..拉里接手孵蛋
...Larry is in charge.
交给拉里  她千万个放心
Larry, whom she trusts implicitly.
对拉里来说 这不是小菜一碟吗？
I mean, how hard could it be?
他需要做的是在琼离开的几分钟内
All he has to do is guard the eggs for a couple of minutes
照顾好这几枚蛋
while Joan is away.
干得好.. 拉里！
You're doing great, Larry.
你行的.. 来吧！
You got this.
加油.. 顶住!
没错.. 确认过眼神非亲生的
You stick with it. And yep, he's gone.
这下大事不妙
This is probably not good.
拉里？
Larry?
拉里 回来！
Larry, come back!
对！ 没错！
Yes! Yes!
快啊.. 拉里.. 不..不
Oh, come on, Larry. No.
你个蠢货！
You dumb bag of.
晕~你个番茄炒蛋！
Oh, scrambled eggs!
真是个混蛋！
What an idiot.
我原以为这里地方偏僻
I thought the whole point of this insane location
能更好地保护它们的鸟蛋免受捕食者侵害
was to protect them from predators.
对于琼和我现实中的妈妈来说 这是个不幸
Unfortunately for Joan, and my mom in real life,
白颊黑雁是终生结伴而行的
geese mate for life.
所以她只能跟他一起了
So she's stuck with him.
孩子们也一样
And so are his chicks.
欢迎来到这个世界.. 小家伙们！
Welcome to the world, little guys.
爸爸妈妈会照顾你们的
Mom and dad are gonna take care of you.
爱你们.. 喂你们..
Love you, feed you,
带你们认识世界
introduce you to the world.
好吧.. 那真是太不负责任了
Well, that was wildly irresponsible.
然而 不管这小黑雁身在何处.. 呃..
毫无疑问.. 它一定过得很好
And wherever that chick is, uh, it's no doubt thriving.
好吧.. 目前来看黑雁夫妇...
Okay, no one's defending
..也只能眼看掉崖的孩子听天由命了
accidentally kicking your kid off a cliff.
但根据数据统计显示：白颊黑雁的雏鸟存活率
But the stats say a 50% survival rate
能达到百分之五十已经相当不错了
that's, is pretty decent for a barnacle goose.
我想说 如果拉里是人类
I mean, if Larry were a human,
这恐怕够他在进监狱里呆一辈子了
I mean, he'd be rotting in jail, of course.
∮ 你必须强调积极的一面 ∮
∮ You've got to accentuate the positive ∮
只希望他别再犯错误了
Let's just hope he doesn't make any more mistakes.
∮ 和消极的一面 ∮
∮ ...the negative ∮
∮ 紧紧抓住... ∮
∮ Latch on to the... ∮
不要因为断奶过程很麻烦
Don't put off weaning
就拖延下去
just because it's messy.
你越早开始.. 麻烦就越少
The sooner you start, the less trouble you'll have.
父母接下来要面对的重要阶段就是断奶
The next major milestone a parent faces is weaning.
但与此同时.. 我们当中有些父母会耗费数小时
But while some of us spend hours
精心准备营养品
prepping nutritious offerings
以满足宝宝娇嫩的肠胃
perfect for delicate little tummies,
一些父母却有其他的想法
some parents have other ideas.
这是吉米
This is Kimmy.
相对于所有哺乳动物而言
She has one of the smallest brains relative to size
她的大脑是最小的
of any mammal.
宛如未成熟的核桃般大小
It's the size of an underdeveloped walnut.
但没有关系啦.. 真的没有关系
But that's okay, that's okay,
因为她大部分时间只会做三件事：
because most of the time she only has to do three things:
吃叶子...
eat leaves,
消化叶子...以及睡觉
uh, digest them,and sleep...
一天睡22小时
for 22 hours a day.
哟.. 这生活过的那叫一个羡慕啊！
That is aspirational,by the way.
但那是因为昨晚喝多了龙舌兰酒
But due to a wild tequila-soaked night
开玩笑的.. 考拉不喝龙舌兰酒
a while back--I'm kidding, koala's don't drink tequila.
瞧那熊样.. 没猜测的话这是典型的肾亏
I think, but it would explain the rampant STDs.
可吉米现在还有新任务要做
Kimmy now has another thing to do:
照顾好这颗小小的核桃脑袋
take care of this little baby walnut brain.
在育儿袋里待了几个月后
And after a few months in the pouch,
是时候尝尝它的第一次固体大餐
it's time for his first solid meal.
∮ 如果你今天走在森林里 ∮
∮ If you go down in the woods today ∮
∮ 你一定会给我一个大惊喜 ∮
∮ You're sure of a big surprise ∮
∮ 如果你今天走在森林里 ∮
∮ If you go down in the woods today ∮
∮ 你最好化个妆去 ∮
∮ You'd better go in disguise ∮
但是吉米.. 她不会用勺子喂食
But Kimmy, she doesn't bother with spoon-feeding
或者用手抓食物喂食
or finger food.
她为了宝宝的第一餐
She's been preparing something very special
筹备了一些特别的东西
for baby's first meal.
如果你觉得反刍的"蒂克勒鼠"女士尸体已经够糟糕的话
And if you thought regurgitated Mrs. Ticklemouse was bad,
等着瞧吧
just wait.
小家伙只需要低下头...
..做好进食的准备就行了
Junior just has to put his head down and prepare to eat...
嗯嗯.. 对
mm-hmm, yep.
那是... 好吧.. 那就是粪便.. 没错
Mm, that is... Okay, that's poop. Yep.
∮ 今天是泰迪熊的好日子... ∮
∮ Today's the day the Teddy Bears have their pic- ∮
显然 对于《国家地理》来说
这画面描述会不会太有违和感？
Apparently that's a bit graphic for National Geographic?
但据说 这种疯狂行为背后也有其道理
But I'm told there's a method to this madness.
桉树叶含有大量毒素
Eucalyptus leaves are toxic
而这种毒素能杀死她的幼崽...
..幼崽一旦食用 后果不堪设想
and would kill her little junior, big time.
但是妈妈的小礼物里藏着一种秘密成分
But mommy's little gift has a secret ingredient.
吉米的“婴儿食品”实际上含有一种特殊的细菌
Kimmy's "baby food" actually contains a special bacteria
可以消除毒素
that can digest the toxins
给幼崽提供一个良好的成长开端
that will give junior the best start in life.
非专业人士请勿在家轻易尝试
Just maybe don't try it at home.
人类的婴儿食品可能看起来也像粪便
Human baby food may also look like poop,
但我向您保证.. 那绝对不是...
but I assure you it's not.
我意思..它是..它最终会变成粪便
I mean, I mean, it's, it's, it will be turned into poop,
但不行.. 你知道的..你不用那样做
but no, you know, you don't--
尿布就是用来解决这问题的
that's what diapers are for.
你可以看到 当我们很小的时候
You can see how completely we depend on others
我们完完全全地依赖他人
when we're very small.
当然 随着年龄的增长
Of course, as we grow older,
我们大多数人开始为自己奋斗
most of us begin to strike out for ourselves,
我们开始培养独立的能力
we begin to develop something called self-reliance.
所以到了某个时候
So there comes a time
孩子们必须学会独立面对
when kids must learn to go it alone.
而让他们掌握所需的生活技能
And equipping them with the life skills they need
对任何的父母来说都是一项艰巨的任务
is a tall order for any parent.
所以这位诞下了二十只幼崽的狐獴妈妈？
So this meerkat mom of tw-tw-twenty?!
她干脆选择了摆烂
She doesn't bother.
因为有众多孩子的一大好处在于
Because the beauty of having so many kids is that the siblings
兄弟姐妹之间可以相互学习 对吧？
can teach each other the ropes, right?
而我的兄弟们非常熟悉各种生活技能
My brothers were amazing with rope.
他们掌握着各种生活的窍门
Oh, they knew all kinds of knots.
不管怎样 他们似乎很好地适应了这里的生活环境
Anyway, yep, they seem perfectly well adjusted.
接下来.. 4周大的奥林...
Next to go through mom's school of hard knocks
..将要接受妈妈地狱式训练
is four-week-old Olin,
而他即将迎来一生中最惊人的打击
and he's about to get the shock of his life.
在过去的一个月里 妈妈一直照顾他
For the past month, mom has been nurturing him
并且满足他的一切需求
and taking care of his every need.
但现在是时候面对现实了 小子！
But it's time to confront reality, junior.
你现在是个男子汉了
You're a man now.
妈妈决定离开自己的幼崽
Mom's ripping off the Band-Aid
并且将他的学业交给他的兄弟姐妹来负责
and leaving his education to his brothers and sisters.
根据我以往的经历
Which I can tell you from personal experience,
嗯 这是个糟糕的主意
well, that's a terrible idea.
第一课：选择正确的朋友
Lesson one, choosing the right friends.
奥林需要学会挑选
Olin needs to learn to pick out
合适的伙伴一起玩耍
the right kind of pals to play with.
嗯 这家伙看起来挺友善的
Well, this guy looks friendly.
这个也不错
Friendly.
不.. 不是巴里
Nope, not Barry.
别.. 别.. 别.. 千万别惹那家伙
Don't, no, no, don't mess with that guy.
一切进展得很顺利
It's all going great.
直到他哥哥出现模仿他哥哥做了一件事
Until his older brother does what older brothers do:
让你惹上了大麻烦
gets you into major trouble.
妈妈会在这个时候提供一些指导吗？
Is mom gonna offer any guidance at this point?
不会
No.
幸运的是 他们很快意识到这不是
Fortunately, they soon realize this is not someone
你想要找的伙伴
that you want to play tag with.
这只是你和你哥哥之间经历的
It's just another thrilling and slightly traumatic adventure
又一场惊险刺激的冒险
而你妈妈永远不知道这事
with your brother that mom will never, ever hear about.
给个B+吧
Let's call that a B+.
第二课：寻找食物
Lesson two, finding food.
其基本的技术是挖掘虫子
Basic technique for this is digging for grubs.
我看过《狮子王》
And I've seen Lion King.
但如果你觉得奥林的哥哥坏透了
But if you thought Olin's brother was bad,
他的姐姐詹梅西正要把他
his sister James is about to introduce him
介绍给一只...蝎子
to a face full...of scorpion.
她之后可能会和她的朋友们拿这个事开玩笑
She'll probably laugh about it with her friends later,
在奥林接受治疗的时候.. 他就会发现..
while you sit in therapy, you know,
她们会用粗糙的袜子人偶来重现整件事
reenacting the whole thing with crude sock puppets.
现在妈妈该出手制止了吧
Surely mom's gotta step in now,
她怎么能让这种事发生
there's no way that she's gonna let...
好吧.. 眼睛都不闪一下
Okay, not a chance.
我想.. 痛苦嘛..  那也是学习当中的一部分
I guess pain is, you know, it's part of the learning process.
好样的！ 奥林！
Bravo, Olin!
这份成绩可够他炫耀一辈子了
This report card might just make it to the fridge.
第三课：当心陌生人
Lesson three, stranger danger.
如果说那件事是狐獴必须学习的
If there's one thing meerkats need to learn above all else,
那就是警惕潜在危险
it's looking out for danger,
尤其来自空中的危险
especially from above.
所有的兄弟姐妹都已经跑回了洞穴里
All the other kids head back to the den.
但奥林还没意识到危险的来临
But Olin hasn't realized the lunch break is over.
现在只剩下妈妈了
The only one left is mom.
这次她总该挺身而出了吧？
Will she finally step in now?
我是说 这里真的有
I mean, there are literally
很多种英雄行为供她选择
so many heroic options available here;
可以和鹰展开搏斗.. 可以跑过去救奥林...
you fight the hawk, you could run to his rescue,
..还可以冲上去挡在孩子前面
throw yourself in the path of danger.
结果呢？
Well?
就是这样？
That's it?
那谁都能做到
That was definitely the bare minimum.
好吧.. 很有效.. 但你们知道.. 说实话...
Okay, it's effective, but you know, a little phoned in
..这有点敷衍
if I'm being honest.
最后奥林没有沦为鹰的猎物
At least Olin ran away in the end.
还能活着回家.. 所以...
But he's still alive, so
我们就给他合格吧
I guess we can call it a pass.
你这个胆小鬼
You little coward.
而对于那些"直升机式"父母们来说
And for all those helicopter parents out there,
向隐秘的动物英雄学习吧
learn from the underdogs.
只要适度的冷漠
A bit of healthy disinterest,
些许可疑的兄弟姐妹粗心监管
a dash of questionable sibling oversight,
你的孩子就很快学会独立了
and your kids learn self-sufficiency fast.
好的 我们回头再看看拉里
Okay, we're gonna check back in on Larry,
一只牢底坐穿的白颊黑雁
a barnacle goose in the doghouse.
还有拉里的两只幸存幼崽
Larry's two surviving babies,
这句话说着有点令人难受
which is a disturbing sentence to say,
他们才一天半大
they're just a day and a half old.
所以拉里和琼
So, Larry and Joan,
他们会一直在这里守护
they're going to stay right where they are.
不会？ 哦.. 不.. 他们要离开了
No? Oh. No, they're leaving.
他们要跟自己窝说拜拜了
They're leaving.
他们马上出发了.. 他们要走了
They're definitely go--they're gone.
对于羽翼丰满的成年黑雁来说 这很容易
Easy if you have fully grown wings.
但幼崽们必须另觅奚径
But the chicks have to find a different way
才能到达地面
of getting to ground level.
但问题是：这里距离地面约244米高
There's just one small problem: the 800-foot drop.
没有飞行的翅膀就意味着
No flight feathers equals high likelihood
两个小家伙坠崖身亡的机率很大
of plummeting to your death.
最终从一只雏鸟变成一块血迹斑斑的石头
Starting as a baby chick and ending as a blood-soaked rock.
会是这样吗？拭目以待
Or does it?
让我们到悬崖边上去看吧
Let's go outto the edge of the cliff.
啊呀！
Ahh!
好吧 非专业人员切勿模仿！
Whoops, there he goes.
对于大多数的人来说坠落通常是很严重的事
For most of us, the fall would be a bad thing,
但对于黑雁来说 则是值得去冒的风险
but for these geese that's a calculated risk.
科学研究表明 雏鸟必须在出生后
Science has worked out chicks have to jump
36至72小时内进行跳跃
between 36 and 72 hours old.
跳得太早.. 它们没有长出足够的绒毛
Any earlier, they don't have enough fluff
来缓冲坠落的速度
to slow their fall.
跳得太晚.. 那它们骨骼就变得过于坚硬和脆弱
Any later, and their bones are too hard and brittle
无法承受撞击而存活
to survive the impact.
好了.. 科学验证的时候到了
Okay, science, over to you.
希望你知道现在自己在做什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
哦哟.. 开始！
Uh-oh!
哦.. 不..不要..hold住！
No, no, no, no, no, oh.
嗯.. 这
Well, that...
摔太惨了
Oh, that was brutal.
哦..不 他看起来应该没事
Oh, no, he does seem to be okay.
天那.. 巴比Q
Oh! Yikes.
那个..25%的生存机率并不算丢人
You know, 25% is nothing to be ashamed of. Mm-mm.
好吧.. 小家伙.. 你看着办吧
Okay, little guy, it's all you.
加油！你能行的！
You got this.
你的兄弟姐妹遭遇不测可能他们运气不佳罢了
Just because your siblings met a horrible, graphic demise
这并不代表你也注定要失败
doesn't mean that you're doomed, too.
根据我对蹦极这项运动的了解而言
From what I know about base jumping,
实际上我对此几乎一无所知
which is, you know, almost nothing,
太好了.. 我觉得他这次一定能成功的
this is good, I think he's got a real shot here.
稍为向左靠一点
Left a bit.
啊...左一点...左.左.左...再左一点!
Ah, left, left a bit, left a bit, left a bit, left a--
好咧...保持住!
Okay, hold that.
保持住...对...稳住姿态!
Hold that, hold that, hold that.
上帝！
Oofff!
情况不太妙.. 别灰心.. 振作点
Not ideal, shake it off, shake it off.
哦..不.. 那个.. 呜
No, no, no, no, that's--oofff!
对...着陆前保持你帅气英姿
Yeah, you gotta stick that landing.
惨不忍睹~老天爷！
Nope, that's hard to watch.
好了~恭喜你成功着陆！
Okay, we're on the snow.
我滚呀滚呀滚
And we're still going.
继续滚
Still going.
滚出个大西瓜
And still going.
他还活着吗？
Is he even alive?
这些真情出演很贵
These shows are expensive,
所以我们稍后再默哀
so we'll do the moment of silence later.
哦...快瞧！
Oh, look!
...它奇迹般活了下来
He did, in fact, survive.
多亏了那边那位“年度好爸爸”袖手旁观
No thanks to father of the year over there.
别担心 相信在未来的日子里
Don't worry, you'll grow to have a more nuanced
能培养出一种更微妙
and advanced sense of resentment
更高级的怨恨感
in many years to come.
我不认为拉里的育儿之道是正确的
I'm not gonna defend Larry's parenting choices,
他是个愚昧透顶的老爸
he's a reprehensible father,
呃.. 老实说.. 他最后的雏鸟之所以还活着...
uh, but frankly, his last chick is alive,
并不是他的功劳  全凭小家伙钢铁般的意志力
not because of him, but, you know, despite him.
但现在至少这家伙还有父母的陪伴...
But at least it still has its parents,
这点要比某些动物好多了
which is more than we can say for some.
所以  我们回过头来看看
So, we're back to where we started.
那位获奖者却是那个付出最少努力的家长
With the parent who wins the prize for the least effort--
慢着 这还能得奖吗？
wait, there's a prize for that?
哦
Oh.
当然 这还不包括所有缺席的父亲们
Of course that's not counting all of the absentee fathers.
像这只汤氏瞪羚 谁也不知道
The Thomson's gazelle,heading out who knows where
她的小孩一生下来就去了哪里
as soon as her tiny offspring exited her birth canal.
好吧  现在是时候看看他会遭遇些什么
Well, now the moment of reckoning has come.
此时此刻  可怜的小瞪羚
The moment when her innocent little calf
将不得不面临着
will have to face the consequences
妈妈的慵懒作风所带来的后果
of mom's lazy-ass approach to motherhood.
现在他将面临各种被吃掉的可能
There are so many ways it could be eaten.
或许被追捕.. 然后被开膛破肚
He could be chased down and, and disemboweled.
撕成碎片
Shredded to ribbons.
甚至不知道这些捕食者会对他做什么
You don't even want to know what she'd do to him.
或者会更惨 被胡狼无情地肢解
Or worse, be ruthlessly dismembered by jackals.
那些因为《小鹿斑比》而深受其害的人们来说
To those of you still traumatized by Bambi,
抱歉
I am sorry.
我和我的团队正在不遗余力地
Me and my team are working relentlessly
寻找射杀小鹿斑比妈妈的猎人
to find the hunter, uh, who shot Bambi's mom
并把它绳之以法
and bring him to justice.
哦.. 这慢镜头.. 不.. 不.. 不.....
Oh, the slow motion, no, no, no, no, no.
这悲伤 戏剧性的配乐
The sad, dramatic music.
我想小詹梅西马上就要见到斑比妈妈了
I think Junior's about to meet Bambi's mom.
等等 这是谁？程咬金吗？
But wait, who's this?
就像我们从泰克勒鼠女士的悲惨遭遇中得知那样
You see, as we learned from Mrs. Ticklemouse's sad demise,
大自然真是神秘莫测总是喜欢捉弄人们
Mother Nature is nothing if not a master of the misdirect.
事实是 这位妈妈迷失了
It's true that mom here wandered off,
让刚出生的婴儿独留于家中
left her newborn baby alone,
那些专门捕食幼崽者有机可乘
surrounded by serial baby-eaters,
奇怪的是 这还是我第一支乐队的名称
which is weirdly the name of my first band.
原来这一切都是妈妈的调虎离山之计
But it's because she didn't want to draw attention to him.
实际上 她一直都在远远地注视着
Truth is, she was always watching from afar.
所以当胡狼发现孩子的一刹那
So when the jackals do find the baby,
她能在0.3秒内从懒妈
she can go from lazy-ass to kick-ass
变成非一般角色
in 0.3 seconds.
因为这是为人父母的英雄本色
Because that's the thing about parents.
所谓人无完人金无足赤
We're not always perfect.
我们难免会犯错
We make mistakes.
有时候我们简直糟糕透顶了
Sometimes we seem downright terrible.
但往往到了最后
But at the end of the day,
在关键的时刻...我们总能挺身而出
when it really matters, we've got this.
又让他跑掉了...
And she's gone again.
你是在跟我开玩笑吗？
Are you kidding me?!
我没有生气.. 我没有.. 我只是有点失望
I'm not mad, I'm-- no, I'm just disappointed.
我的口气听起来像极了我妈
Oh, I sound like my mother.
嘿.. 塔米
Hi, Tam-Tam.
所有的哺乳动物中
One of the most interesting
负鼠堪称是最奇特妈妈了
of all mother animals is the opossum,
无论她走到哪里
who carries her litter of babies with her
负鼠妈妈都会背着一窝孩子
wherever she goes.
那需要强大的体能
She needs healthy boundaries.
有时难免会弄丢几只
Sometimes one or two do fall off,
但它们通常能够找到
but they usually find their way back to mother
回到母亲和其他幼崽身边的路
and the other babies.
除非你跑得比他们快
Not if you run faster than they can.
有时负鼠妈妈会用尾巴倒挂着小家伙
Sometimes the opossum hangs by her tail.
也许是想减轻些负担
Probably trying to shake a few off.
但很快他们都安定下来
But soon they all settle down
然后安静地小憩
for a quiet nap.
终于 世界都清静了
Ohh, finally. Peace.
制作人：月 朗 风 清
DOOD LUCK FOR YOU!!